<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation for appointing commissioners for granting of licences and dispensations for retailing of wines.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1660-1685 : Charles II)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B19552</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886168_192483</idno>
  <idno type="VID">192483</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248538346</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R036148</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C3315</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 21.h.1[194]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.21.f.1[30l]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 1851.c.8[178]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R036148</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225569</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886168</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886168e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B19552)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 192483)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C10:1[194]; C9:3[148]; C18:1[177])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation for appointing commissioners for granting of licences and dispensations for retailing of wines.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1660-1685 : Charles II)</author>
                  <author>Charles II, King of England, 1630-1685.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by John Bill and Christopher Barker, printers to the Kings most Excellent Majesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1663/4 [i.e. 1664]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dates are given according to Lady Day dating.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end: Given at Our Court at Whitehall, the 16th day of February, 1663/4. in the sixteenth year of Our reign.</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: Arms 73; pursuance Wine- 2) limited Acts.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Wine and wine making --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Wine and wine-making --  Taxation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:192483:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms of Charles II</figDesc>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q>H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>NI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure> By the King. A PROCLAMATION For appointing Commissioners for granting of Licences and Dispensations for Retailing of Wines.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>CHARLES R.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas by Our Royal Proclamation (bearing date at Our Court at <hi>Whitehall,</hi> published in pursuance of a late Act of Parliament, entituled, <hi>An Act for the better ordering and selling of Wines by Retail</hi> (amongst other things) We did Will and Require all Our loving Subjects who were Retailers of any Wine or Wines within Our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and Town and Port of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> to appear and address themselves to Our Agents for the time being, at their respective Offices, and to Contract, Conclude and Agree with them for Licences and Dispensa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions to Sell and Vtter Wine by retail. And whereas We have setled upon Our dear and most intirely beloved Brother, <hi>James</hi> Duke of <hi>York,</hi> the Rents, Issues, and Profits of the said Wine-Licences, towards the maintenance and support of Our said dear Brother, together with all the Powers and Authorities setled in Vs by the said Act, which are now also setled upon Our said dear Brother by Act of Parliament in that behalf made and provided. And whereas Our said dear Brother hath thought fit to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>assume the said Farm and Revenue, and to Manage the same by His Commissioners and Agents: In pursuance whereof, and of the Powers and Authorities given by the said Act, Our said dear Brother <hi>James</hi> Duke of <hi>York,</hi> hath under His Hand and Seal Authorized and Deputed <hi>Henry Brounckard</hi> Esq; Sir <hi>John Colliton</hi> Knight and Baronet, and <hi>Richard Downs</hi> Esq; to be Agents and Commissioners for granting Licences and Dispensations for selling and ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering all kind of Wine and Wines by Retail within the places and limits aforesaid, in the place and stead of Sir <hi>Richard Braham</hi> Knight and Baronet, Sir <hi>Nicholas Armorer</hi> Knight, and Sir <hi>George Smith</hi> Knight, <hi>Stephen Fox, Richard Mason,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Oudart,</hi>
               <abbr>Esqs</abbr> We do hereby strictly Charge and Command all Our Subjects who are Retailers of Wine within Our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and Town and Port of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> That they and every of them do appear and address themselves unto the said <hi>Henry Brounckard,</hi> Sir <hi>John Colliton</hi> and <hi>Richard Downs,</hi> or to any Two of them, at their Office in <hi>Durham</hi> Yard in the <hi>Strand,</hi> at the several time and times herein after limited and appointed, then and there to Contract with the said Agents and Commissioners, at such Rates and Prices as they shall agree, for Licence and Dispensation for Retailing Wines; and likewise such as have formerly Contracted with any of Our aforesaid Agents or Commissioners, or their Officers, or paid any money to them for Rents, Fines, or any other ways concerning Wine-Licences, that they bring with them such their Licences, and Acquittances to manifest such their respeceive Contracts, and Moneys paid, and that they duely and punctually pay all their Arreara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges and growing Rents, unto the said Agents and Commissioners herein nominated, sitting in <hi>Durham</hi>-Yard afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said. And We do hereby further Declare Our Royal Will and Pleasure is, That all and every person and persons who are Retailers of Wine, or that shall desire to have Licence and Dispensation to Retail Wine within Our said Dominions, and dwelling within Eighty miles of Our City of <hi>London,</hi> shall and do appear before the said Agents or Commissioners at their Office aforesaid, and shall and do Agree, Contract and give such good Security for payment of their Rents, and performing of Covenants, as the said Agents or Commissioners shall like and approve, and likewise pay their Arrears of Rent, at or before the last day of this present <hi>February;</hi> And that all Retailers of Wine, and such as desire to Retail Wine, and dwelling One hundred and sixty miles from <hi>London,</hi> shall appear and perform as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, at or before the Five and twentieth day of <hi>March</hi> next; and that all other person or persons as aforesaid, inhabiting at a greater distance from <hi>London</hi> then One hundred and sixty miles, shall appear and perform as aforesaid, at or before the Three and twentieth day of <hi>April</hi> next. And We do hereby Declare, That if any person or persons whatsoever, in any City, Town-Corporate, or other place or places, shall by vertue or colour of any Letters Patents, Grants, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts, or Authorities whatsoever, not warranted by the said Acts, shall presume to Vtter or Retail any Wine or Wines whatsoever, without making such Contract, and giving Security for payment of their Rents within the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective times herein limited, they and every of them are and shall be liable to the Penalties and Forfeitures in the said Act Set and Imposed upon all such who Vtter and Retail Wine without Licence, contrary to the said Acts, and are to be proceeded against as the Act directeth. And We do straitly further Charge and Command all Sheriffs, Mayors, Bayliffs, Constables, and all other Our Officers whatsoever, to be aiding and assisting unto the said Agents or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners of Our said dear Brother, for the exact obeying and putting in execution of this Our Royal Proclamation, and the said Acts of Parliament. And We do hereby Declare to all Our loving Subjects, That it will be good and acceptable service to Vs, in any of Our said Subjects, to prosecute such Offenders who shall presume to Sell or Retail any Wines without Licence as aforesaid, for which they shall receive the Reward and Advantage by the said Acts proposed, being the moyety of Five pounds for every such offence committed.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at Our Court at <hi>Whitehall</hi>
                  </hi>
                  <date>
                     <hi>the 16<seg rend="sup">th</seg> day of <hi>February,</hi> 1663/4. in the Sixteenth year of Our Reign.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>God save the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>John Bill</hi> and <hi>Christopher Barker,</hi> Printers to the KINGS most excellent Majesty. 1663/4.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>